

MAHDI **NAZARI**

Tehran, Iran · +98 930 28 96 950

Email: mahdi_nazari@ut.ac.ir , Portfolio: www.m3hdi7.wixsite.com/mahdi-nazari born in January 1995

Senior Android Developer with **six** years of experience, also developing games with **Unity** for about two years, and cracking mobile applications. I have been programming since I was sixteen; therefore, I have worked with a lot of programming languages and have a strong knowledge of object-oriented programming. I was a math and computer **Olympiad competition selected**, as a result, I have a **strong mathematical background** and I'm very good at problem solving.

SKILLS

- Strong knowledge in Kotlin and Java, experienced in programming with C++ and C#
- Lead Architecture design discussions to create highly powerful and highly scalable applications
- Strong implementation knowledge of algorithms, designing for performance and scalability apps
- Accountable for the production of high-quality code on a personal level adhering to all software engineering quality standards/benchmarks
- Demonstrable ability to deliver projects on time, with high quality, and within budget
- Good knowledge of development tools, environment, utilities, and common libraries
- Demonstrable knowledge of UDP and HTTP/S and how apps interact with RESTful APIs
- Coroutines, Flow, Hilt, Dagger, LiveData, RxJava, Room, DataStore, Navigation, Paging, WorkManager, View and Data Binding, Lifecycle, and other Android common libraries

EDUCATION

2021 - PRESENT

M.A. GAME DEVELOPMENT AND REASEARCH, TH KÖLN, COLOGNE GAME LAB (GERMANY)

2013-2017

B.SC. MINING ENGINEERING, UNIVERSITY OF TEHRAN, COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING (IRAN)

- Teaching Assistance in "Computer Programming with C++" course for two semesters.
- Tutor of Programming with C++.

2009-2013

DIPLOMA. OSVEH EXEMPLAR HIGH SCHOOL

• Tutor of Mathematics and Physics for high school students.

HONORS

EDUCATIONAL

- Iran Computer Olympiad Competition (IMO) selected (2012).
- Iran Math Olympiad Competition (IMC) selected (2012).

ATHLETIC

- Gold medal in Basketball competition (2013)
- Gold team-medal in Ping Pong competition (2008)

EXPERIENCE

JAN 2019 - PRESENT

SENIOR ANDROID DEVELOPER & UNITY GAME DEVELOPER, FREELANCE

- Implement an Ethash, Ethereum GPU based miner with OpenCL.
- Collaborate with a German startup for a musical social application.
- Develop a map navigator application base on MAPS.ME, change UI completely, and add more features, change most codes of JAVA part, didn't touch the engine part (C++).
- Develop an online real-time(lock-step) 2D archery game in Unity using Photon SDK.
- Cracking some android application (can't mention their name in my cv).

NOV 2018 - JAN 2019

SENIOR ANDROID DEVELOPER, PAK CHARKH IRANIAN (BDOOD BIKES)

- Collaborate with the product manager, business analyst, backend, designers, etc.
- Make "lock module" branch on the repo and develop the module from scratch, lock module is the part of the app that communicates with a chip installed on bikes through BLE to open and close bikes' lock.
- Fix application bugs.

NOV 2017 - NOV 2018

MID-LEVEL ANDROID DEVELOPER RASA-PARDAZ AYANDE

- Manage, build up, and lead client and service-man Android applications
- Work with the product owner, backend, etc. as a semi-remote developer.
- Reorganize their customer application to have robust and extendable code base.
- Design UI/UX and develop their service provider app from scratch.
- Implement a logging system using Firebase.

AUG 2016 - NOV 2017

ANDROID DEVELOPER & GAME DEVELOPER, MELOW

- Make a 2D game engine from scratch with android SDK in JAVA, on a lowest drawing-level part (Surface View).
- Gain a lot of knowledge about game engines and how they work under the hood.
- implement multi-threading and concurrency in threads to gain best performance.
- Build a custom physics engine for real-time 2d collision detection.
- R&D on detect noisy data, modify and fit them in their correct position in which they must have been alongside the other data using some linear interpolation calculation, all in real-time.
- Working knowledge of augmented reality implementation in Unity.

JAN 2016 - AUG

JUNIOR XAMARIN DEVELOPER, FIRST EURASIA E-COMMERCE

- Working knowledge of design patterns and best practices in OOP.
- Learn with Agile Methodology, and working with the Scrum framework.
- Working knowledge of the general cross-platform app development, architectures, trends, and emerging technologies.
- Working knowledge of the Google material design principles and tools.
- Working with the Push notification mechanism (SignalR).
- Finding solutions for a lot of XAMARIN FORM bugs in the deployment process, and use MVP architecture to overcome.
- Working knowledge of TFS source control.
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency and application optimization.